Jeff Meyer

Georgetown, MA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Jeff-Meyer/fb47eef3ba64d46b

Full stack software IT specialist with multiple years experience in applications design, development, and deployment. Experienced working with a wide range of technologies and environments in all phases of the application life cycle; from requirements gathering, design and construction, end-to-end testing, to deployment and support. Strong knowledge of object-orientated analysis and design with emphasis on software re-usability, extensibility, and security. Experienced in leading joint application development sessions and managing communications with clients, team resources, and vendors. Continuous commitment to ongoing learning.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Vestmark - Wakefield, MA - July 2014 to Present

Development and support of the VestmarkONE fintech platform. Skill sets: Java, Eclipse, Hibernate, EJB, XML, REST, SOAP, Git, Gradle, MSSQL, Spring, Agile methodology utilizing Atlassian stack.

Senior Software Engineer

Helium Inc., a division of RR Donnelley - Andover, MA - March 2013 to July 2014

Accomplishments

Development of new functions and features of the Helium content management platform.

Skills Used

Java, JSP, Spring, Hibernate, JQuery, KendoUI, Tomcat, SQL, Eclipse, XML, SVN, Amazon Web Services, Maven, SVN, Agile methodology

Sr Programmer Analyst

Quest Diagnostics, Inc - Lenexa, KS - 2010 to March 2013

Skill sets:

- Java, Oracle BPEL, Oracle ESB, JDeveloper, PL/SQL, EJB, Oracle Database, XML/XSL, CVS, SVN, Web Services, .Net C#, Visual Studio 2008 and 2010

Business domain:

- Laboratory diagnostic testing and reporting.

Accomplishments/Projects:

- Case View Web Successfully completed design, development, enhancement, and support of a hybrid system based on front-end .Net Web Forms Presentation Layer communicating via web services to a Java/ EJB Domain and Persistence Layer.
- Case Central Performed support and enhancement of an Oracle ESB and BPEL file processing framework based on Oracle SOA Suite. This framework interfaces with service providers to send laboratory orders and receive results.

Sr Programmer Analyst

Argus Health Systems, Inc - Kansas City, MO - 2006 to 2010

Skill sets:

Business domain:

- Java, Tapestry, Hibernate, Spring, XML/XSL, JavaScript, DB2, SQL, CVS, SVN, RAD/Eclipse, Web Sphere,
Web Services, EJB, Clear Quest, DBVisualizer, DBAtisian, UML

- Pharmaceutical information processing.

Accomplishments/Projects:

- E-Prescribing Successfully completed design, development, enhancement, and support of a Tapestry/Spring/Hibernate web application used to allow remote doctor offices to request patient drug coverage eligibility verification and patient medication history via electronic communications between the doctor's office, the RxHub clearinghouse, and Argus Health Systems. Performed top-to-bottom design from database model, persistence and domain layer logic, to user interface screens.
- Web Support Perform problem analysis, data analysis, implement technical fixes and enhancements, and report application performance metrics for all current Argus web applications. Scope of technologies ranges from web services, EJBs, legacy frameworks, to current web platforms. Manage communications with various stakeholder parties, both internal and external. Typically work on numerous projects simultaneously.

Sr Programmer Analyst

LabOne Inc - Lenexa, KS - 2004 to 2006

Skill sets:

- Java, Struts, XML/XSL, JSP, JavaScript, iBatis, Oracle, PL/SQL, PostgreSQL, CVS, Eclipse, Tomcat, Apache, Linux, Visual Basic, SeeBeyond, Health Level 7, UML

Business domain:

- Laboratory diagnostic testing and reporting.

Accomplishments/Projects:

- Member Solutions Successfully completed design, development, enhancement, and support of a Java/Struts web application used to allow remote clients to view clinical and toxicology laboratory results and specimen chain-of-custody images. Also provides users with a list of state-by-state collections sites, gathered from an external vendor data feed, and a custom build user authentication and permissions framework.
- Clinical Abstractor Designed and developed a framework of Oracle PL/SQL packages designed to capture the existing functionality of the legacy clinical laboratory result reporting codebase into an object-orientated framework of independent packages. Involved extensive research and analysis of the existing reporting business logic and code to allow the business domain functions to be 'abstracted' out of the legacy code and databases into a reusable framework. My tasks comprised all aspects of the systems development life cycle. Performed analysis, design, development, unit and system testing, and deployment.
- LabOne Link Performed detailed system analysis of legacy Visual Basic thick client application, including process models, interface & functional documentation in preparation for system re-design project. The LabOne Link application is a thick client application that is installed at participating clinics and doctors offices to allow them to remotely order laboratory tests and receive results from LabOne.

Sr Systems Analyst

DST Systems, Inc - Fairway Development - Kansas City, MO - 2001 to 2004

Skill sets

- Java, XML/XSL, Web services, JSP, JavaScript, CSS, DHTML, DB2/SQL, Swing/SWT, CVS, WebSphere Studio Application Developer, Eclipse, Tomcat, Apache, BEA WebLogic, MVC Architecture, UML Design, Windows XP, Linux

Business domain:

- Stock transfer recordkeeping and reporting.

Accomplishments/Projects:

- Employee Access - A Java/EcommCore system designed as a single-sign on framework to link together up to four separate back-end client systems under a single login. Completed full life-cycle project with a small team of developers to gather user requirements, perform analysis and design, code, test, and successfully deploy the application as an intranet website for external clients.

- Identity Verification Designed, constructed, tested, and deployed a Java/EcommCore framework to utilize XML over SSL to integrate with an external vendor's web service for generating a personal identification verification based on multiple identifiers. The Identity Verification framework, or IDV, in turn created an XML API to allow other application to connect to IDV services.
- RPMSWeb Designed, constructed, and deployed this Java application that provides a GUI front end to a legacy mainframe reports repository. The application initiates communication thru one or more CICS regions to trigger a COBOL on the mainframe that perform report retrieval functions and return the data back through the CICS region, to the Java application. Once returned, the data is rendered using XML/XSLT for GUI display.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Information Systems

DeVry Institute of Technology - Kansas City, MO 1992

SKILLS

Java, JavaScript, Spring, Hibernate, Maven, Subversion, Git, REST, SOAP, JQuery, MSSQL, Eclipse, Gradle, Oracle, DB2, SQL, .Net, C#, Visual Studio, SQL Server, Agile/Scrum (10+ years)

LINKS

http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeff-meyer/6/592/b76/